archilovers.com 2019-06-17

# Archilovers App

Last updated: 05/24/2018

Welcome to our website. Please read our Privacy Policy carefully. It is applicable in the event of you visiting our website and simply deciding to browse the content as well as if you use the enhanced services. If you have not already done so, we also invite you to read the ["Term of use"](http://www.archilovers.com/help/terms) page because it contains important information on safe browsing, on the Privacy Policy and on the control systems adopted.  This policy is in accordance with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/679, which protects individuals regarding the processing of personal data. According to this regulation, this processing will be based on the principles of propriety, lawfulness, transparency, and the protection of personal privacy and rights. 

##  1\. Who processes your personal data 

Edilportale.com SpA, with its registered office in Bari (Italy) in via Loiacono 20 VAT registration number and SSN 05611580720, REA 429007, (hereinafter Edilportale), is the data controller of the personal data of the users registered through the websites that it owns and manages, such has [www.archiproducts.com](http://www.archiproducts.com/), [www.edilportale.com](http://www.edilportale.com/), [www.archiportale.com](http://www.archiportale.com/), [www.archilovers.com](http://www.archilovers.com/). The registration on one of these websites allows the use of the services dedicated to the users who are registered on all the websites of our network by using the same credentials. The address to use the rights set out in the GDPR EU 2016/679 is [privacy@edilportale.com](mailto:privacy@edilportale.com). Edilportale.com Spa wants to be sure that users’ personal data are safe, so it gives instructions on privacy and security to its employees, and it makes sure that these instructions are strictly applied in the company. 

## 2\. Our policy

Everyone has the right to protect the personal data belonging to them. Edilportale.com SpA respects the right of its users to be informed regarding the collection and other processing operations of their personal data. In processing data that can directly or indirectly identify you personally, we try to respect the principle of strict necessity. For this reason, we have set up the website so that use of your personal information is kept to a minimum and to exclude the processing of your data when the purpose of the specific activity can be achieved by using anonymous data (like, for instance, in market research aimed at the improvement of services ) or by other means, which allow the person concerned to be identified only if needed or requested by the authorities and police forces (such as, for example, but not limited to data on traffic and on the time you spend on the website or your IP address). Decisions about the purposes and methods of processing your personal data and the tools used, including the security profile, are made by Edilportale.com SpA, as personal data controller of the users. This Privacy Policy provides you with all the information necessary to understand how we collect and use the information to identify the users of our websites. For any further information on our Privacy Policy you can contact us at the following email address: [privacy@edilportale.com](mailto:privacy@edilportale.com). or by post at Edilportale.com SpA, via Loiacono, no. 20, 70126, Bari   
**Edilportale Data Protection Officer** : In order to assert the rights described in articles 15 to 22 of the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR), you can send a written request to the following address: Edilportale s.p.a. Via N. Loiacono, 20/B, 70126 Bari, Italy, or write to our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@edilportale.com](mailto:dpo@edilportale.com). 

## 3\. How we use your personal data and for what purposes

Your personal data (address or phone number, your user ID and password, e-mail address) are collected and processed by Edilportale.com SpA for purposes strictly related to the proper use of the website and its information services, with information also provided by third-party advertisers. Your personal information may also be used in other processing operations, however, in a manner in line with these purposes. In particular, your personal data may be processed for the following purposes: 

  * \- within the website access process, to provide you with private functionalities, such as the modification of your personal access and profile data;
  * \- to receive our newsletters and DEMs which are an intrinsic part of our services; so, if you consent to the processing of your data, Edilportale.com SpA will send you emails with technical and commercial information, regarding other companies as well. These emails (also called DEM or newsletters) are part of the services offered by Edilportale.com SpA;
  * \- to provide you with assistance services; 
  * \- to send your final requests aimed to obtain information and to receive informative material, e.g., catalogues, brochures, price lists, to our advertisers;
  * \- to process and manage your orders (deliveries, invoices, customer service). The recipients of your personal data, if any, are our payment or payment security providers, our delivery providers, our business partners. The recipients of your personal data, if any, are our payment or payment security providers, our delivery providers, our business partners. These businesses are obliged to protect your personal data and to use them in accordance to the regulation and the legal requirements.
  * \- to sending your contact information to the brands advertised on our website, of which you will download catalogues, BIM and CAD files, or whose website you will visit via our pages. This is to permit the same brands to send you further information about the products you have consulted, in compliance with privacy regulations

Your personal data is processed mainly electronically and in some cases also in printed matter. Your personal data will be stored in a way that allows you to be identified for the time strictly necessary for the purpose for which the data was collected and subsequently processed and, in any case, within the limits of the law. To ensure that your personal information is always correct and up-to-date, relevant and complete, please inform us of any changes at: [privacy@edilportale.com](mailto:privacy@edilportale.com). Your personal information will not be disclosed to third parties for purposes not permitted by law or without your explicit consent. Moreover, your personal data may be disclosed to law enforcement or judicial authorities, in accordance with law and prior to formal request by these authorities, for instance within anti-fraud services. Your data will also be accessible to data processing chiefs as indicated in par. 2 and for the specific purposes indicated in the same paragraph. In all these cases, your consent is not required. Your personal information may be disclosed to the public only with your consent and only while providing the services rendered by our websites. Your personal information will not be transferred abroad. Please note that Edilportale.com SpA processes personal data of its users only for purposes strictly related to the provision of the services rendered through its websites and to inform you about new commercial initiatives closely related to the activities and services of the website. Edilportale.com SpA processes your personal data for direct marketing purposes, also by email, with your consent alone. 

## 4\. What happens if you do not communicate your personal data to Edilportale.com S.p.A.

The communication of your data to Edilportale.com SpA and, in particular, personal information, your email address, your postal address and phone number are required for receiving the newsletter and for accessing the free services provided by its network or for providing other services on the website requested by you or when your data is necessary for fulfilling legal obligations or procedures. Any refusal to communicate the data necessary for such purposes to Edilportale.com SpA may make it impossible for Edilportale.com SpA to provide the services through its websites, like sending you newsletters, providing information or printed materials, sending you news about conferences, seminars and courses, providing assistance services and correctly fulfilling legal obligations and procedures. Failure to communicate the data may, as appropriate, provide a legitimate and justified reason for Edilportale.com SpA to not execute or terminate the services requested by you. Communication of additional data to Edilportale.com SpA, other than that required for fulfilling its services is, however, optional and has no consequence on the use of the website. Depending on the circumstances and, if necessary at the time, we will duly inform you of the compulsory or optional requirement of communicating your personal data to Edilportale.com SpA. We will inform you of the compulsory or optional requirement of your personal data, by placing an asterisk (*) before compulsory information necessary to provide the services on our websites. Please note that the failure to disclose optional personal data does not entail any obligations or any disadvantages. 

## 5\. Whom do we communicate your personal data to

Your personal data may be made available to third party companies who process the data independently only to carry out the operations described on our websites as indicated in paragraph 3 above and only when such a purpose is not incompatible with the purposes for which your data was collected and subsequently processed and, in any case, in accordance with the law. The other possible companies which we will send these data to are edilportale.com SpA’s client business that, after signing contractual clauses, have given adequate guarantees on the use of these data with the same objectives as the ones that were set out when these data were gathered (requests of information, requests of quote, etc.). The data will not be communicated, sold or otherwise transferred to third parties, without the users having been informed beforehand and, with their consent, when it is required by law. 

##  6\. How we collect your information on our sites

While using and browsing on our websites, some personal information may be collected automatically (by means of so-called "Cookie"), like, for example, the collection of the user's IP address and other information relating to browsing the website or the user's preferences expressed when choosing the services offered by the site. This information and data are collected directly and automatically by the web site and as part of its operational functions. Further details on how we collect our data can be found on our [cookies information page](http://www.archilovers.com/help/cookies). 

## 7.1 Security measures

We have adopted security measures so as to minimize the risks of destruction or loss, even accidental, of the data itself, of unauthorized access or data processing not permitted by or not compliant with the purposes of collection set out in our Privacy Policy. However Edilportale.com SpA cannot guarantee its users that the measures adopted for the security of the website and of the transmission of the data and information limit or totally exclude any risk of unauthorized access or data loss. We recommend that you ensure that your computer has suitable software installed for protecting data transmission on the web, both incoming and outgoing (like updated antivirus systems) and that your Internet service provider has taken appropriate measures for the security of data transmitted over the web. 

## 7.2 Trusted Shops Buyers Protection 

If you choose to subscribe to the Trusted Shops Buyers Protection, your personal data will be transmitted to Trusted Shops. Further details on the Trusted Shops Privacy Policy can be found at the link <http://business.trustedshops.co.uk/imprint/>

## 7.3 Registration of payment details

In case of credit card payments, all payment details, e.g., credit card or debit card number, expiration date, security code, will be protected and managed by our systems in order to complete the purchase. The payment details and information entered in the financial system (credit card number, security codes) are encrypted using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) technology and will not be stored in any way on our systems. 

## 8\. Your rights 

You are always entitled, pursuant to the articles 15 to 22 of the Regulation EU 2016/679, to the following rights and obtain: 

  * \- confirmation from Edilportale.com SpA of the existence or not of personal data concerning you, 
  * \- you are also entitled to obtain information from Edilportale.com SpA about the origin of your personal data, 
  * \- the purpose and methods of processing your personal data, 
  * \- the logic applied if the latter is carried out with the help of electronic means 
  * \- the identity of the data controller and of the data processing chief; 
  * \- the names of subjects or categories of subjects to whom the personal data may be communicated or who can learn about them like, for example, the data processing chiefs. 
  * \- When possible, information regarding the period of storage and processing limitations; 
  * \- Data portability, that is to say the possibility of receiving these data in a structured format that is readable by an automatic device and of sending them to another processing owner without any impediments. 
  * \- The update, the anonymous rectification or the integration of your personal data. 
  * \- erasure, anonymization or blocking of data that have been processed unlawfully, including data whose retention is unnecessary for the purposes for which they have been collected or subsequently processed; 
  * \- certification to the effect that the operations as per letters i) and j) have been notified, as also related to their contents, to the entities to whom or which the data were communicated or disseminated, unless this requirement proves impossible or involves a manifestly disproportionate effort compared with the right that is to be protected. 
  * \- Withdrawal of consent at any moment without jeopardizing the lawfulness of processing based on the consent given before the withdrawal; lodge a complaint to the competent authority (authority responsible for privacy) 

You will, however, have the right to oppose totally or partially:   
a) on legitimate grounds, to the processing of personal data concerning you, even though they are relevant to the purpose of the collection;   
b) to the processing of personal data concerning you, where it is carried out for the purpose of sending advertising materials or direct selling or else for the performance of market research or commercial communication surveys.  
c) to the automated decisional process concerning individuals with profiling.

You may freely and at any time exercise your rights within the limits of the law, by making a request to Edilportale.com SpA to the email address [privacy@edilportale.com](mailto:privacy@edilportale.com). to which we will give appropriate feedback. Edilportale.com SpA. può rifiutarsi di dar seguito a richieste che risultino futili, moleste, danneggino la privacy di altri o siano eccessivamente difficili da soddisfare. You can unsubscribe from our periodical newsletters at any time by clicking on the link "Unsubscribe from newsletter" in the footer of all our newsletters, sent upon your explicit request. 

## 9\. Contacts

We hereby inform you that you may exercise your rights against the data controller under the European law. If you are concerned about your data, you have the right to request access to the personal data which we may hold or process about you by writing an email to [privacy@edilportale.com](mailto:privacy@edilportale.com). 

## 10\. Storage times

Your data are stored for the time needed to reach the aims set out in this regulation, unless the law asks for or allows a longer storage period.
